Guide to the Heather Lewis Papers 1965-2002 (Bulk 1980-1999) MSS 132 MSS.132
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VIII: Administrative Materials, 63088
  - Subseries F: Administrative Correspondence, 63121
    - Mary Ingraham Bunting Institute of Radcliffe College, 1995; 63138 (Box 10, Folder 390)
    - Mattes, Jed, undated; 63137 (Box 10, Folder 391)
    - Miller, Michael. Voice Literary Supplement, 1998; 63136 (Box 10, Folder 392)
    - PEN American Center, 1995; 63135 (Box 10, Folder 393)
    - Schinto, Jeanne, 1994; 63134 (Box 10, Folder 394)
    - Seventeen Magazine, 1994; 63133 (Box 10, Folder 395)
    - Silverberg, Ira. Serpent's Tail, 1996; 63132 (Box 10, Folder 396)
    - Smyth, Sarah. Martin Secker and Warburg, 1994-1995; 63131 (Box 10, Folder 397)
    - Sosland, Cynthia, 1987; 63130 (Box 10, Folder 398)
    - Talese, Nan. Doubleday, 1993-1994; 63129 (Box 10, Folder 399)
    - Urban, Amanda, 1994; 63128 (Box 10, Folder 400)
    - Weil, Wendy, 1997; 63127 (Box 10, Folder 401)
    - Witherspoon Associates, Inc., 1994; 63126 (Box 10, Folder 402)
    - Wylie, Aitken and Stone, 1996; 63125 (Box 10, Folder 403)
    - Yaddo, 1994; 63124 (Box 10, Folder 404)
    - Lenna [no last name], 2000; 63123 (Box 10, Folder 405)
    - Correspondence from readers, undated; 63122 (Box 10, Folder 406)
  - Subseries G: Calendars and contacts, 63114
    - Business cards [other people's], undated; 63120 (Box 10, Folder 407)
    - phone lists, undated; 63119 (Box 10, Folder 408)
    - Day planner calendar, 1986-1987; 63118 (Box 10, Folder 409)
    - Day planner calendar, 1988; 63117 (Box 10, Folder 410)
    - Day planner calendar, 1991; 63116 (Box 11, Folder 411)
    - Day planner calendar, 2002; 63115 (Box 11, Folder 412)
  - Subseries H: Resumes, applications, calls for papers, 63109
    - Resume, undated; 63113 (Box 11, Folder 413)
    - Fellowship application statement of purpose, undated; 63112 (Box 11, Folder 414)
    - Proof reading applications, 1991-1995; 63111 (Box 11, Folder 415)
    - Calls for papers, potential projects, undated; 63110 (Box 11, Folder 416)
  - Subseries I: Writing Workshops, 63098
    - "Y Workshop", 1987; 63108 (Box 11, Folder 417)
    - Writing workshop, 1994; 63107 (Box 11, Folder 418)
    - Outwrite, 1995; 63106 (Box 11, Folder 419)
    - Writer's Voice, 1996; 63105 (Box 11, Folder 420)
    - Dialogue with yourself by Ira Progoff, undated; 63104 (Box 11, Folder 421)
    - Mundis Notes, undated; 63103 (Box 11, Folder 422)
    - Poetry vocabulary, undated; 63102 (Box 11, Folder 423)
    - Presentation, undated; 63101 (Box 11, Folder 424)
    - Screenplay notes, undated; 63100 (Box 11, Folder 425)
    - Typewriter settings, undated; 63099 (Box 11, Folder 426)
  - Subseries J: Publisher Files, 63093
    - Bertelsmann, 1998; 63097 (Box 11, Folder 427)
    - Ordfront Publishing House, Stockholm, 1999; 63096 (Box 11, Folder 428)
    - Reed Publishing, 1993; 63095 (Box 11, Folder 429)
    - Swanson Literary Agency, undated; 63094 (Box 11, Folder 430)
  - Subseries K: Miscellaneous, 63089
    - Ardache Corporation Board of Directors Meeting [Ann Rower], 1994-1997; 63092 (Box 11, Folder 431)
    - MNN certificate of Completion, 1995; 63091 (Box 11, Folder 432)
    - Miscellaneous, undated; 63090 (Box 11, Folder 433)
- Series IX: Research, 63073
  This series contains research materials including Heather Lewis's subject files and notes. Materials are arranged by date where possible, then in alphabetical order.
  - Subseries A: Notes, 63084
    - Academic Notebook, 1990; 63087 (Box 11, Folder 434)
    - Academic notebook, undated; 63086 (Box 11, Folder 435)
    - Academic Notebook, undated; 63085 (Box 11, Folder 436)
  - Subseries B: Subject Files, 63074
    - Earhart, Amelia, undated; 63083 (Box 11, Folder 437)
    - "Female Mutilation", undated; 63082 (Box 11, Folder 438)
    - Holiday, Billie. Includes copy of Billie Holiday's FBI file, 1947-1990; 63081 (Box 11, Folder 439)
    - Horseback riding, undated; 63080 (Box 11, Folder 440)
    - Lesbian and Gay issues, undated; 63079 (Box 11, Folder 441)
    - Nico, undated; 63078 (Box 11, Folder 442)
    - Prostitution. Including Coyote Howls. [Additional materials in oversize], undated; 63077 (Box 11, Folder 443)
    - Smith, Patti. [Additional materials in oversize], undated; 63076 (Box 11, Folder 444)
    - Straw, Syd, undated; 63075 (Box 11, Folder 445)
- Series X: Images, 63013
  This series includes candid and professional photographs, negatives and a piece of oil-crayon artwork. Where possible, photographs and negatives are matched and located in subseries A. Subseries are organized chronologically where possible, undated materials are arranged alphabetically. Please note that the dates provided for the photographs are printing dates, not the date the image was captured.
  - Subseries A: Photographs, some with matching negatives, 63027
    - Trees and landscape, May 1965., 63072 (Box 11, Folder 446)
    - Heather Lewis, 1969; 63071 (Box 11, Folder 447)
    - Playing, houses and landscape, 1972; 63070 (Box 11, Folder 448)
    - Trees, 1975; 63069 (Box 11, Folder 449)
    - Tennis, flowers, May 1975, 63068 (Box 11, Folder 450)
    - Pets, July 1975, 63067 (Box 11, Folder 451)
    - Tennis, September 1975, 63066 (Box 11, Folder 452)
    - Candid shots of Heather Lewis and friends, boating, pets. January 1976, 63065 (Box 11, Folder 453)
    - Swimming, boating, band, hood ornament. August 1976, 63064 (Box 11, Folder 454)
    - Water, sky, boating. January 1978, 63063 (Box 11, Folder 455)
    - Flower, quilt, still lifes, windows, building supplies, 1978; 63062 (Box 11, Folder 456)
    - Pets, children, 1979; 63061 (Box 11, Folder 457)
    - Girl, November 1979, 63060 (Box 11, Folder 458)
    - Wax museum, 1981; 63059 (Box 11, Folder 459)
    - Band [Connie?], 1982; 63058 (Box 11, Folder 460)
    - Children, December 1986, 63057 (Box 11, Folder 461)
    - Sunset, 1991; 63056 (Box 11, Folder 462)
    - Beach, August 1994, undated; 63055 (Box 11, Folder 463)
    - Beach and young boys., undated; 63054 (Box 11, Folder 464)
    - Billie Jean King, undated; 63053 (Box 11, Folder 465)
    - Class photograph: Mrs. McRoberts, undated; 63052 (Box 11, Folder 466)
    - Contact sheets, miscellaneous, undated; 63051 (Box 11, Folder 467)
    - Demolished building, undated; 63050 (Box 11, Folder 468)
    - Heather Lewis, polaroids, undated; 63049 (Box 11, Folder 469)
    - "Heather and Jesse's North Carolina Tour" Heather Lewis and Jesse Cohen, House Rules book signing. With annotations, undated; 63048 (Box 11, Folder 470)
    - Horseback riding, single image from contact sheet, undated; 63047 (Box 11, Folder 472)
    - Horseback riding, Budd Studio, undated; 63046 (Box 11, Folder 473)
    - Horseback riding, Freudy Photos, undated; 63045 (Box 11, Folder 474)
    - Horseback riding, The Portrait Group, undated; 63044 (Box 11, Folder 475)
    - Horseback riding, photographer unknown., undated; 63043 (Box 11, Folder 476)
    - Horseback riding, Linda McFarland, undated; 63042 (Box 11, Folder 477)
    - Horseback riding, Reiner Niewisch, undated; 63041 (Box 11, Folder 478)
    - "Memorabilia" photograph of woman, undated; 63040 (Box 11, Folder 479)
    - Pets, sports, undated; 63039 (Box 11, Folder 480)
    - Pets, undated; 63038 (Box 11, Folder 481)
    - Pets, candid, undated; 63037 (Box 11, Folder 482)
    - Pets, undated; 63036 (Box 11, Folder 483)
    - Polaroid, undated; 63035 (Box 11, Folder 484)
    - Polaroids, with annotations, undated; 63034 (Box 11, Folder 485)
    - Still life photographs of rejection letter from New Yorker magazine., undated; 63033 (Box 11, Folder 486)
    - Slides, undated; 63032 (Box 11, Folder 487)
    - Trees and snow, undated; 63031 (Box 11, Folder 488)
    - Web, undated; 63030 (Box 11, Folder 489)
    - Wedding, undated; 63029 (Box 11, Folder 490)
    - Women, undated; 63028 (Box 11, Folder 491)
  - Subseries B: Unmatched Negatives, 63016
    - Band, performing, undated; 63026 (Box 11, Folder 492)
    - Buildings, landscape, stuffed animals, car, undated; 63025 (Box 11, Folder 493)
    - Family, Christmas, undated; 63024 (Box 11, Folder 494)
    - Horseback riding, undated; 63023 (Box 11, Folder 495)
    - Horseback riding, undated; 63022 (Box 11, Folder 496)
    - Palm trees, house, beach, foot, undated; 63021 (Box 11, Folder 497)
    - People, candid, undated; 63020 (Box 11, Folder 498)
    - Pets, outdoor tennis, undated; 63019 (Box 11, Folder 499)
    - Pets, trees, people, undated; 63018 (Box 11, Folder 500)
    - Tennis, undated; 63017 (Box 11, Folder 501)
  - Subseries C: Other Images, 63014
    - Oil crayon drawing. [located in map case]., undated; 63015 (Box 11, Folder 502)
- Series XI: Juvenilia, 62996
  This series includes materials from Heather Lewis's childhood such as yearbooks, baptismal certificate and children's literature. This series is arranged chronologically where possible. Undated matererials and children's literature are in alphabetical order at the end of the series.
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1965; 63012 (Box 11, Folder 503)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1966; 63011 (Box 11, Folder 504)
  - Christmas Card from Heather Lewis, with photograph, 1967; 63010 (Box 11, Folder 505)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1967; 63009 (Box 11, Folder 506)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1968; 63008 (Box 12, Folder 507)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1969; 63007 (Box 12, Folder 508)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1970; 63006 (Box 12, Folder 509)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1971; 63005 (Box 12, Folder 510)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1972; 63004 (Box 12, Folder 511)
  - "The Searcher" Cisqua School yearbook, 1973; 63003 (Box 12, Folder 512)
  - Confirmation and Baptism certificates, 1974; 63002 (Box 12, Folder 513)
  - "Reflections" vol. 20, John Jay High School, Katonah New York. Student poetry journal., 1979; 63001 (Box 12, Folder 514)
  - The Cisquapedalian, student writing compilation, undated; 63000 (Box 12, Folder 515)
  - American Women of Achievement: Amelia Earhart, Aviator, 1987; 62999 (Box 12, Folder 516)
  - Doty, Jean Slaughter. Summer Pony. 1973, 62998 (Box 12, Folder 517)
  - Doty, Jean Slaughter. Winter Pony. 1975. inscribed by author to Heather Lewis., 62997 (Box 12, Folder 518)
- Series XII: Printed Materials, 62978
  Materials in this series are arranged alphabetically.
  - Connie-n-the Linguistiks posters, undated; 62995 (Box 12, Folder 519)
  - Doonesbury cartoons, undated; 62994 (Box 12, Folder 520)
  - Hair Care, undated; 62993 (Box 12, Folder 521)
  - Hewlett Packard Laser Jet printer user's manual, undated; 62992 (Box 12, Folder 522)
  - "Julia" film poster. located in map case, undated; 62991 (Box 12, Folder 523)
  - Map of the West Indies. located in map case, undated; 62990 (Box 12, Folder 524)
  - Miscellaneous images: Mark Rothko cards and calendar page Tuesday August 2, 1994., undated; 62989 (Box 12, Folder 525)
  - Mourner's Kaddish, Riverside Memorial Chapel., undated; 62988 (Box 12, Folder 526)
  - New Yorker "Critic at Large" Ethan Mordden. Article about Judy Garland, cartoon of Oldest Living Confederate Widow., 1990; 62987 (Box 12, Folder 527)
  - Playbill "The Hairy Ape", 1997; 62986 (Box 12, Folder 528)
  - Publisher's Weekly, 1988; 62985 (Box 12, Folder 529)
  - "Theirs was the Kingdom", undated; 62984 (Box 12, Folder 530)
  - tickets, undated; 62983 (Box 12, Folder 531)
  - Tourism pamphlets, undated; 62982 (Box 12, Folder 532)
  - Transportation information, undated; 62981 (Box 12, Folder 533)
  - Village Voice, April 26, 1994. Music and dance sections., 62980 (Box 12, Folder 534)
  - Video sales, undated; 62979 (Box 12, Folder 535)
- Series XIII: Objects and Artifacts, 62969
  This series includes objects such as a trophy, library card and pen. All of these objects are located in box 13 except the red leather datebook.
  - Trophy. "Congratulations! A star is born!, undated; 62977 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_56f8d98b4f3cb0412b9c06627a258a2c)
  - Writing paper, undated; 62976 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_4ca516eda247d72224cdd84519a0d687)
  - Heather Lewis's New York Public Branch Libraries card, undated; 62975 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_7d6f32d1090ecd01038ecf3a8ed64dfa)
  - Pin, "Club Can-Do. Kids called to CARE", 1999; 62974 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_adcb4ba7b1eb42e2c15ed63c05a18cd1)
  - AIDS ribbon pin with rainbow ribbon attached., undated; 62973 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_2251b86571c54038e2ac2fef9ec0db72)
  - Brown leather wallet, undated; 62972 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_635b3c3c2861a151914b8ce4266d8d64)
  - Mont Blanc pen, undated; 62971 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_2f890e8a568b4ac1f68f3a8869d42db5)
  - Red leather day planner with pen. Inside: business cards and notes, Arizona driver's license and US passport, 2002; 62970 (Box 11, Folder 412)
- Series XIV: Media, 62940
  This series contains two subseries. Subseries A: Computer media includes 3.5 inch floppy disks. Subseries B includes all other media including 5.25 inch floppy disks, compact disks and Heather Lewis's laptop computer.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiovisual and born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
  - Subseries A: 3.5 inch floppy disks, 62949
    - 132.0001 "Old hard drive files excerpts", undated; 62968 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_00fd76d2cd78ac0e5718c85fbe444310)
    - 132.0002 "Old Hard Drive Files excerpts", 61 files, 1989-1993; 62967 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_3d4fd54c780a280ed8d237ef26dcf6bf)
    - 132.0003 "Old Files" unopened, damaged, undated; 62966 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_b42a47b85da1ab80d6c93fed8e342773)
    - 132.0004 "Three", damaged, undated; 62965 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_68b565628958f22c15171aa2931ddc4e)
    - 132.0005 "Bloodline", 1997; 62964 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_552d0ffbe7d0b6091b125d81b0701b1d)
    - 132.0006 "Resume FAX", 1995-1996; 62963 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_85d64fbf0b23afa0803036b1d855c5ba)
    - 132.0007 "Poetry Excerpts p. 1", undated; 62962 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_437c9e447f10bdaf344924179c7f303f)
    - 132.0008 "House Rules and Excerpts", 1993-1995; 62961 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_4aad581fef36865946eb1837313357b2)
    - 132.0009 untitled, 1998; 62960 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_62783df02e173882624b4c7e109b48be)
    - 132.0010 untitled, 1998; 62959 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_3610ab2998613e7ded1be317add27001)
    - 132.0011 untitled, 1996-1999; 62958 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_5feabb0d5f5cd638baa30ae6b32a056e)
    - 132.0012 untitled, 1996-1998; 62957 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_a65491b3180294520d88e90d3222e134)
    - 132.0013 untitled, 1995-1998; 62956 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_d6165eeab1cbcf3464e618464400e697)
    - 132.0014 untitled, damaged, undated; 62955 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_96130f8b7b9ea2c84e85cf5be1b29f02)
    - 132.0015 untitled, damaged, undated; 62954 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_710cabe25b70ae30bfab45e737d5d40d)
    - 132.0016 untitled, 1996-1999; 62953 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_6e5ea3d00449dbf2baa098a21f63ddb7)
    - 132.0017 untitled, 1995-1997; 62952 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_29ba00428d326ef7a3fecf497192f434)
    - 132.0018 untitled, 1995-1997; 62951 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_4afc94084a13d110deaadacad0d63459)
    - 132.0019 untitled, 1995-1998; 62950 (Box 13, Folder data_value_missing_f4bd5aad64dc00fe3c63a875caa98a44)
  - Subseries B: Other media, 62941
    - sony microcassette, MC30, undated; ID: 132.0020; 62948 (Box 13, Media ID: 132.0020)
      Currently unavailable until duplication occurs.
    - Audio CD. Heather Lewis Nightlight Reading. Linda Yablonsky introduction, 51 seconds, Heather Lewis 22:38, March 9, 1994; ID: 132.0021; 62947 (Box 13, Cd 132.0021, Case 132.0021)
    - Audio CD. Heather Lewis memorial., June 12, 2002; ID: 132.0022; 62946 (Box 13, Cd 132.0022, Case 132.0022)
    - Heather Lewis memorial audio CD., 2002; ID: 132.0023; 62945 (Box 13, Media ID: 132.0023)
    - "HR-1 (FE)" 5.25 inch floppy disk, Bonus personal computer disk 2S/2D, undated; ID: 132.0024; 62944 (Box 13, Media ID: 132.0024)
    - "HR-P2 and 3 (FE)" 5.25 inch Bonus personal computer disk, undated; ID: 132.0025; 62943 (Box 13, Media ID: 132.0025)
    - Toshiba Satellite T1910/200 laptop computer with power cords. Serial number: 06429428, undated; ID:; 62942 (Box 14, Media ID:)
- Oversize Series I: Journals, 62938
  - Journal, July 1982-August 1982, 62939 (Box 15, Folder 17B)
- Oversize Series III.E: House Rules - Publicity Materials, 62934
  - Literary press., 1993; 62937 (Box 15, Folder 144)
  - House Rules reviews, 1994; 62936 (Box 15, Folder 149)
  - The Village Voice (39:40) House Rules review. October 4, 1994., 62935 (Box 15, Folder 154)
- Oversize Series IV.A: Second Suspect - Manuscripts, 62932
  - The Second Suspect, dust jackets., 1993; 62933 (Box 15, Folder 187)
- Oversize Series VI.D: Other Writing - Essays, Letters., 62930
  - "Voice Literary Supplement" Heather Lewis's review of A.M. Homes's The End of Alice., 1996; 62931 (Box 15, Folder 251)
- Oversize Series VIII.F: Administrative Materials - Administrative Correspondence., 62928
  - Max Eilenberg., undated; 62929 (Box 15, Folder 382)
- Oversize Series IX.B: Research - Subject Files., 62925
  - Subject File: "Prostitution"., undated; 62927 (Box 15, Folder 443)
  - Subject File: "Patti Smith", undated; 62926 (Box 15, Folder 444)
- Oversize Series X.A: Images - Photographs., 62923
  - Photographic portrait of Heather Lewis for Village Voice article. Klaus Schoenwiese - photographer., undated; 62924 (Box 15, Folder 471)
- Oversize Series X.C: Images - Other Images., 62921
  - Drawing - oil stick., undated; 62922 (Folder 9)
- Oversize Series XII: Printed Materials., 62917
  - Doonesbury cartoons., undated; 62920
  - "Julia" film poster., undated; 62919 (Folder 8)
  - Map of the West Indies., undated; 62918 (Folder 10)